we did it we integrated the tiny human
brains we grow in jars into robots
something that literally every science
fiction series said will end terribly
really really terribly a lab out of UC
San Diego the matur lab decided to let a
little brain organoid control a robot
spider in an effort to let it start to
integrate with its environment initially
they found that unstimulated brain
organoids fired around 3,000 times per
minute but when they stimulated it and
allowed it to learn in the environment
it ended up firing 300,000 times this is
a lot more similar to what we see in
newborn babies we already know that the
brain organoids even without stimulation
still end up giving Delta brain waves
which is the kind of brain waves you see
in a pre-term baby or somebody who's
sleeping the brain organoids can form
every structure in the human brain
during development one of the large
issues with it is integrating it with a
circulatory system which we might be
able to do inside of robots maybe one
day my AI robot can actually love me but
in other horrifying dystopian news we're
actually able to use the Gen genomes
that we found from Neanderthal to make
Neanderthal brain organoids to help us
try and figure out how they differed
from us or how similar they were which
leads me to an ethical question we are
allowed to use human brain organoids
right now they seem to have the
developmental brain waves of a pre-term
baby however when we're integrating them
into robots giving them material that
they can actually interact with seems to
get them beyond that developmental stage
at least in what we're seeing right now
would it be more to use Neanderthal
brain organoids